<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:cinclude="http://apache.org/cocoon/include/1.0" xmlns:zs="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
  <leader>03173nz  a2200253n  4500</leader>
  <controlfield tag="001">no2015066987</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="003">DLC</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="005">20150521073522.0</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="008">150520n| azannaabn          |n aaa     c</controlfield>
  <datafield tag="010" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">no2015066987</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="035" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">(OCoLC)oca10170787</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="040" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">UPB</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
    <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">UPB</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="100" ind1="1" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Milner, John D.</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Architect)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="370" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="f">Chadds Ford (Pa.)</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">naf</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="372" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Historic preservation</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">lcsh</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="373" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">University of Pennsylvania. School of Design</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">naf</subfield>
    <subfield code="s">1976</subfield>
    <subfield code="t">2013</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="373" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">John Milner Architects</subfield>
    <subfield code="s">1989</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="374" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Architects</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">lcsh</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="375" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">male</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="667" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Formerly on undifferentiated name record no2005066300</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">The restoration of the Hans Herr House, Willow Street, Lancaster County, Pennsylvania, 1972:</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">title page (John D. Milner)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Stone houses: traditional homes of Pennsylvania's Bucks County and Brandywine Valley, 2005:</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">title page (John D. Milner) jacket flap (architect practicing in Chadds Ford, Pa.; adjunct professor of Architecture, Univeresity of Pennsylvania's School of Design)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Stone houses : traditional homes of R. Brognard Okie, 2013:</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">title page (foreword by John D. Milner) page 4 of jacket (John D. Milner is an architect whose firm specializes in the restoration of historic buildings and the design of new houses that are inspired by the architectural traditions of the past; his firm, John Milner Architects, received the prestigious Arthur Ross Award in architecture for excellence in the Classical Tradition)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">John Milner Architects Design &amp; Preservation, via WWW, May 14, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(John Milner, FAIA, Principle; John Milner is a respected and widely published Architect with a career-long passion for historic preservation and new traditional design; John's preservation experience has been project specific at all task levels from on-site architectural investigation to project management; his particular expertise is in the detailed analysis of historic buildings to document their physical and cultural history, and the development of strategies and technical procedures for their restoration, conservation and adaptive reuse; his new residential and building designs are inspired by his extensive knowledge of historic precedent and often respond to sensitive environmental contexts; after receiving his Bachelor of Architecture degree from the University of Pennsylvania, he was employed as a staff architect for the Historic American Building Survey and Branch of Restorations of the U.S. National Park Service; John established his architectural practice in 1968, and developed a multi-disciplinary historic preservation firm that included historians, architects, archeologists and planners; in 1989, John and his business partner, Mary Werner DeNadai, formed John Milner Architects to focus on architectural restoration, rehabilitation and design; John served as Adjunct Professor of Architecture at the University of Pennsylvania's School of Design from 1976 until 2013; he enjoys domestic and foreign travel to study architectural precedent which informs the firm's contemporary designs; he also studies and collects American and European fine and decorative arts)</subfield>
  </datafield>
</record>