<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:cinclude="http://apache.org/cocoon/include/1.0" xmlns:zs="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
  <leader>02445nz  a2200217n  4500</leader>
  <controlfield tag="001">no2011188116</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="003">DLC</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="005">20111209075252.0</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="008">111207n| azannaabn          |n aaa     c</controlfield>
  <datafield tag="010" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">no2011188116</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="035" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">(OCoLC)oca09055974</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="040" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">UPB</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">UPB</subfield>
    <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="046" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="f">19451112</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="100" ind1="1" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Atwater, William F.</subfield>
    <subfield code="q">(William Felix),</subfield>
    <subfield code="d">1945-</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="370" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Dallas, Tex.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="373" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">United States. Marine Corps</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="373" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">U.S. Army Ordnance Museum</subfield>
    <subfield code="s">1989</subfield>
    <subfield code="t">200711</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="375" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Male</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">World War I tech, 2004:</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">title frame (William F. Atwater, Ph. D., Director, U.S. Army Ordnance Museum)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">U.S. Army Ordnance Corps Hall of Fame, via WWW, December 6, 2011</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Dr. William F. Atwater; born November 12, 1945 in Dallas, Texas;  graduated from Berea College, Kentucky, in 1968; commissioned as a lieutenant in the Marine Corps; served for ten years; commanded a rifle platoon in Vietnam; received a Master of Arts in Military History in 1984 and a Ph. D. in Military History in 1985 from Duke University in Durham, North Carolina; served as the Director of the Don F. Pratt Museum (101st Airborne/Air Assault Museum) at Fort Campbell, Kentucky, from 1985 to 1989; served as Director, U.S. Army Ordnance Museum at Aberdeen Proving Ground, Maryland, where he was responsible for one of the largest collections of military hardware in the world at over 13,000 artifacts; has been a featured guest in productions by the Discovery Channel, the Learning Channel, and the History Channel, and consulted for the A&amp;E Channel on such productions as "Brute Force--A History of Weapons at War;" retired in November 2007 after 18 years as the Ordnance Museum Director and 32 years of Federal military and civilian service)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Wikipeidia, via WWW, December 6, 2011</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(William Atwater; born William Felix Atwater; holds a Bachelor of Arts degree in history and political science with a minor in philosophy and religion from Berea College in Berea, Kentucky; commanded a Marine Corps rifle platoon during the Vietnam War where he received the Purple Heart, a Navy Commendation Medal, and a Vietnamese Cross of Gallantry; took over responsibilities at the United States Army Ordnance Museum in 1989; is the contributor on the topic of grenades, mortars, and land mines in the Oxford Companion to American Military History (2000); has appeared as a firearms and ordnance expert in many documentaries regarding military history)</subfield>
  </datafield>
</record>