<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><record xmlns="http://www.loc.gov/MARC21/slim" xmlns:cinclude="http://apache.org/cocoon/include/1.0" xmlns:zs="http://www.loc.gov/zing/srw/">
  <leader>04937cz  a2200373n  4500</leader>
  <controlfield tag="001">no2015129613</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="003">DLC</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="005">20151217121247.0</controlfield>
  <controlfield tag="008">150928n| azannaabn          |b aaa     c</controlfield>
  <datafield tag="010" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">no2015129613</subfield>
    <subfield code="z">sh 86007060 </subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="035" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">(OCoLC)oca10281712</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="040" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">WaU</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">eng</subfield>
    <subfield code="e">rda</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">WaU</subfield>
    <subfield code="d">DLC</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="100" ind1="0" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Daphne</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Nymph)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="368" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="c">Nymphs (Greek deities)</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">Goddesses, Greek</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">lcsh</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="375" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">female</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="375" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Females</subfield>
    <subfield code="2">lcdgt</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="400" ind1="0" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Daphne</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Greek deity)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="400" ind1="0" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Δάφνη</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Nymph)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="400" ind1="0" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Dafne</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Nymph)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="400" ind1="0" ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Dafnis</subfield>
    <subfield code="c">(Nymph)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="667" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Non-Latin script reference not evaluated.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Bernini, Gian Lorenzo. Apollo e Dafne del Bernini nella Galleria Borghese, 1997.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Fux, Johann Joseph. Dafne in Lauro, 1990.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Hughes, John. Apollo and Daphne, 1716.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Strauss, Richard. Daphne, 1996.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Twardowski, Samuel. Dafnis w drzewo bobkowe przemienieła sie, 1955.</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Wikipedia, September 28, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne (Greek: Δάφνη = Daphnē, meaning "laurel") is a minor figure in Greek mythology known as a naiad--a type of female nymph associated with fountains, wells, springs, streams, brooks and other bodies of freshwater)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Infoplease website, September 28, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne, in Greek mythology, a nymph. She was loved by Apollo and by Leucippus, a mortal who disguised himself as a nymph to be near her. When Leucippus betrayed his sex while bathing, the nymphs tore him to pieces. Apollo then pursued Daphne, who prayed to Gaea for aid and was changed into a laurel tree.)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Britannica online, September 28, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne, in Greek mythology, the personification of the laurel (Greek daphnē), a tree whose leaves, formed into garlands, were particularly associated with Apollo. Traditionally, the special position of the laurel was connected with Apollo's love for Daphne, the beautiful daughter of a river god (probably Ladon) who lived a pastoral existence in either Thessaly, the Peloponnese, or Syria. She rejected every lover, including Apollo. When the god pursued her, Daphne prayed to the Earth or to her father to rescue her, whereupon she was transformed into a laurel. Apollo appropriated the laurel for poets and, in Rome, for triumphs. Daphne was also loved by Leucippus, who was killed because of Apollo's jealousy.)</subfield>
    <subfield code="u">http://www.britannica.com/topic/Daphne-Greek-mythology</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Theoi Greek mythology website, September 28, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne was a Naiad nymph of the river Peneios in Thessalia or the Ladon of Arkadia. She was loved by the god Apollon who pursued her until she grew exhausted, cried out to Gaia for help and was transformed into a laurel tree)</subfield>
    <subfield code="u">http://www.theoi.com/Nymphe/NympheDaphne.html</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Encyclopedia mythica, via WWW, September 28, 2015</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne was the daughter of the river god Peneus. Apollo chased down the maiden, desperate for her love, but she wanted nothing to do with him, and she ran from him endlessly. Soon, she grew weary in her running and that Apollo would ultimately catch her. Fearful, she called out to her father for help. As all gods of water possess the ability of transformation, Peneus transformed his daughter into a laurel tree)</subfield>
    <subfield code="u">http://www.pantheon.org/articles/d/daphne.html</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Greek-Gods.info website, September 28, 2015:</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">Nymphs &gt; Daphne (Daphne was a beautiful nymph who loved to hunt and was created by the titaness Gaea, the mother Earth, and the god of the rivers Peneus. Daphne was the first love of Greek god Apollo. When Apollo saw Daphne for the first time, he got struck by the arrows of Eros and madly fell in love with her. However, Daphne was rather indifferent to Apollo and tried to flee. But Apollo didn't want to give up. So he set up in pursuit of Daphne, until finally he caught her and folded her in his arms. Full of despair, Daphne prayed to her mother Gaea for aid to make her disappear. Gaea followed her wish and, all at once, Daphne disappeared off the face of the earth. On the spot Daphne was seen for the last time, a fragrant plant, the sacred laurel tree, grew in Daphne's honor. From then on, the laurel tree became the symbol of Apollo and he was often depicted with laurel leaves on his golden hair.)</subfield>
    <subfield code="u">http://www.greek-gods.info/ancient-greek-gods/nymphs/daphne/</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">The Oxford classical dictionary, 1996</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphne ('Laurel'), daughter of a river-god (usually the Ladon, in Archadia), a wild virgin huntress who caught Apollo's eye. Failing to outrun the god in her attempt to avoid ravishment, at the point of capture she prayed for help from Zeus (or her father) and was metamorphosed into a bay-tree)</subfield>
  </datafield>
  <datafield tag="670" ind1=" " ind2=" ">
    <subfield code="a">Dictionary of classical antiquities, 1956</subfield>
    <subfield code="b">(Daphnē. A nymph, daughter of the Thessalian river-god Pēneius, or according to another story, the Arcadian Lādōn, was beloved both by Apollo and by Leucippus, the son of Œnŏmăus)</subfield>
  </datafield>
</record>